How awful...
酷い…
Those locusts must've eaten up
all the rice before it was harvested.
あのバッタどもに収穫前の稲や作物を残らず食い尽くされたのであろう
Young Master.
若。
I checked the neighboring villages.
近隣の村々を見てまいりました
How are they?
どうであった？
Some have had their fields
overrun by rats.
ネズミに田畑を食い荒らされるなど、
All are suffering
from some form of misfortune.
原因は違えどどの村も災難に見舞われております
Some villages have even been struck
by epidemics.
流行り病に冒された村もあり
Those near the borders are hit the worst.
国境にある土地ほど被害は酷く、
It seems to be spreading inwards.
徐々に領内に広まっているようです
Could it be the demons?
やっぱり…鬼神の仕業かな…
Because we couldn't kill him?
俺たちがあいつを討ち損ねたから…
We must find out.
確かめねばなるまい。
To the Hall of Hell.
地獄堂へ行くぞ！
Please, sir.
お慈悲でございます！
Could you spare a morsel of food
for this child?
どうか…この子に、
ひとかけらの食べ物でも分けちゃあもらえませんでしょうか！
Is that good, Sakichi?
うめぇか？サキチ…
There's still more. Chew well now.
まだまだあっからよぉ…よく噛んで食えぇ…！
I promise you as the man
who looks over this land.
この地を治める者として約束しよう…
I will never forsake you.
決してそなたたちを見捨てはせぬ
Betrayed this world
And it simmers within
Rupturing my innards
Swelling a reddish black
Until the sun burnt skin ruptures
There is a light
in the depths of the seething darkness
Confirming each other's voices
in the distance
As if to stroke with wet fingertips
I'd like to touch you one day
There is a light
in the depths of the darkness
Confirming each other's voices
in the distance
As if to stroke with wet fingertips
I'd like to touch you one day
#20 The story of the Nue
Wow! It's all bright red
everywhere I look.
すげー！どこもかしこも真っ赤っ赤だ！
Dororo.
どろろ！
Oh yeah.
おぉっといけね
We're here to defeat a demon.
ここにはバケモンの退治に来たんだったな。
Seems like lots of people
have been killed around here.
この辺りの山で何人も襲われてるらしいんだけど…
That's funny. I've been to the mountains
in the fall before.
変だな…秋の山なんて初めてじゃないのに。
Why am I so amazed now?
なんでこんなに…
Guess I was too busy trying to stay alive
to notice when I was on my own.
そっか…1人でいたときは生きてくだけで精一杯だったもんな…
I'm going to eat one too.
おいらも食べよっと！
Is this for me?
え…？おいらにくれんの？
For you, Dororo.
どろろのぶん
Bro got me some food...
あにきが…おいらに、食いモンを…
There are four seasons, you see?
Spring, summer, fall, and winter.
あにき…季節にはな、春・夏・秋・冬ってあるんだ
Right now, it's fall.
今は秋でな。
In the fall,
the mountains turn bright red.
秋んなると山ん中が真っ赤に染まるんだよ！
But not red like the color of demons,
I don't think.
真っ赤って言っても、鬼神の色とは全然違うと思うぜ？
It makes you feel so great
just gazing at it.
見てるとなんとも言えずいい気分になるんだ
That's what you call "beautiful."
そういうのを綺麗って言うんだよ…
I only just learned about it, too.
おいらも…さっき知ったんだ。
You'll be able to see it some day.
I know you will.
あにきもいつか、きっと見えるようんなるさ！
Not just mountains. Lots of
beautiful stuff like the sun and clouds.
山だけじゃない。お陽さんとか雲とか、いろんな綺麗なもんがさ！
You're just nodding.
Are you really listening?
うんうんうんって…ホントに聞いてんのかい？
I want to hear more. More of your stories.
だからもっと聞きたい。どろろの話
Bro.
あにき…
You've changed.
なんか変わったな
Yeah, you really have changed.
うん。やっぱり変わったよ。
You're nothing like when I first met you.
出会った頃とは大違いだ！
I got a lot of stuff
I want to tell you about, too.
おいらも…あにきと話したいことがいっぱいあんだ！
But first, let's go beat that demon.
でも、まずはその前にバケモン退治だな
Looking for the demon?
バケモンを探してんのか？
Who are you?
なんだよあんた！
Hey, relax.
そう身構えんなって。
I came to kill the demon, too.
俺もな、バケモンを殺しに来たんだ
I'm Dice-spot Saburota.
俺は賽の目の三郎太ってんだ。
I've been hunting the demon
for about 6 months now.
半年ほど前から、この山でヤツを狙ってる
It's a pretty tough beast.
手強いヤツでなぁ。
I've gone after it many times,
with only this to show for it.
何度もやり合っちゃあ…この有り様よ
Why are you so fixed on killing it?
なんでそこまでして？
It ate my ma.
ヤツにおっかぁを喰われたのよ…
Right in front of my eyes.
目の前でな
Your mama, huh.
おっかちゃんを…
I'll never forget it.
今でも忘れられねぇ…
It's like I've had an empty hole
right here ever since that day.
あのときから…ココにぽっかりと穴が空いちまったようさ
Yeah...
あんた…
Those arms. I see you've been through
a lot with them, too.
その腕、あんたもヤツらに手酷い目に遭わされたみてぇだな。
Must've been pretty frightening.
さぞ恐ろしい思いをしたろう…
Let's go, Dororo.
行こう。どろろ
It comes here on certain days.
ヤツは決まった日にこの岩場に現れる。
Today is one of them.
今日がその日だ
Don't worry, bro is really tough.
大丈夫。あにきは強いんだ
He'll avenge your mama.
必ずおっかちゃんの仇を討てるさ
Yeah, glad to hear that.
あぁ…頼りにしてるぜ
It's coming.
来る
What the heck? Its body...
な…なんだ…あの身体…
It's a jumble of animal parts.
いろんなモンが混ざってらぁ…
Demon!
鬼神！
Go away!
こっち来るな！
Bro!
あにき！はっ…
What the heck are you doing?
何やってんだよあんた！
I see you're pretty good.
少しゃぁやるみてぇだなぁ…
Why are you siding with the demon?
な…なんでバケモンと一緒にいんだよ！
Didn't it kill your mama?
そいつはおっかちゃんの仇だろ？
Killing the demon won't bring Ma back.
バケモン殺したところで、おっかぁは帰っちゃ来ねぇ。
So I'm taking others' lives away instead.
だからよぉ…代わりにこっちが奪ってやるのよ
I let this guy eat up
everyone that passes through here.
山を通りがかったヤツは、みんなこいつに喰わせたぜ。
They all cry and plead for help.
誰もが助けてくれって泣き叫んでよぉ…
It's only then
that I don't feel empty in here.
そいつを見てるときだきゃあ…ココが埋まる気がすんだ…
You...
あんた…
Something is strange at the Hall of Hell.
殿。地獄堂で妙なことが。
One of the demon statues lets out
something like a heartbeat now and then.
時折、鬼神像の1つから鼓動のごとき音が響くのです。
It's faint, yet distinct.
かすかではありますが、間違いなく
I felt it, plain as day,
when the Goddess's head was smashed.
あの菩薩像が砕けたとき、はっきりと感じたのでございます。
That among the 12 demons,
there was one that failed to eat my son.
12の鬼神のうち、あの子を喰い損ねたものがいると。
Now that the Goddess of Mercy is cracked,
your deal has been broken off.
菩薩像が砕けた今、殿との約定は破れました。
The days of prosperity
for this land are over.
この国の安寧の時は…終わりまする
...Dororo.
どろろ
Bro...?
あに…き…
Oh yeah, we fell from that cliff.
そうだ…おいらたち、あっこから落ちて…
That guy...
あいつ…
Dororo.
どろろ
It's nothing. I'll get up.
なんでもねぇ！今起きるよ
I can't.
ダメだ
Dororo.
どろろ
Don't worry, it'll come out in time.
心配すんなって！そのうち抜けらぁ
No, below you.
違う。下だ
You can't with those arms, bro.
その腕じゃ無理だ、あにき…
I will.
なら…
We're almost there, Ma.
もうすぐだぞ、おっかぁ。
Once we cross this mountain,
we'll reach the doctor.
この山を越えれば、医者のいる町だ
I'm sorry for
putting you through this, Saburota.
すまないねぇ…三郎太。
I'll make a name for myself with
this some day.
いずれ俺は、こいつで成り上がる。
And we won't have to sell pelts anymore.
そしたらもう、獣の皮なんぞ売る必要はねぇ
I'll make a good living for us.
せいぜい楽させてやるよ
Oh, Saburota.
三郎太…
Saburota...
三…郎太…
三…郎太…！
The next one.
次だ！
I'll bring another.
次のやつを連れてくる
Or should I feed myself to it?
あるいは…俺を喰らうか？
No, you'll break your arms.
はっ…！だ、ダメだって！壊れちまうよ！
You need them.
あにきの大事な腕だろ
Don't worry, I'll find my way out of this.
大丈夫、こんなの自力で抜け出してやるよ
Dororo.
どろろ！
Move over a bit, son.
ちょっくら…どいてくんな
You're okay now.
もう大丈夫だ
I thought I heard a familiar voice.
聞き覚えのある声がしたもんでねぇ。
I'm glad I made it in time.
間に合って幸いだったよ
You want a body?
身体が欲しいのか
I do.
欲しい
Why?
なぜだ
Because it's mine.
俺の…ものだ…
Bro...?
あに…き…
You're alive?
お前生きてたのか…
Demon...
鬼神…！
So, you have an empty hole here too, eh?
なーんだ…お前もここに、穴が空いてんのか。ヘッ、だが…
But give it up.
無駄よ
Saburota...
三郎太…
Saburota!
三郎太？あぁっ！
What's that...!
あっ…そっ…そりゃ何だい！？
He left her to die, all alone.
見捨てて1人だけねぇ…
Acting like a samurai all the time,
but what a coward.
武士の真似事なんぞして…いざとなったら
I couldn't help it...
がねぇ…んだ…しょうがねぇ…
I couldn't, I couldn't...
Let's go, Saburota.
行くぞ、三郎太。
We'll get revenge.
仇討ちだ
S-Save me!
助けてくれぇ！
Huh.
なーんだ…
It's the same for everyone.
みんなそうじゃねぇか
No!
やめろぉー！
Why? Why don't you run for your life?
ぐっ！なんでだよ！なんでおめぇは逃げねぇんだ！
Aren't you scared? Scream!
怖ぇだろ！？なら叫べ！
Cry! Beg for your life!
泣いて命乞いしろぉ！
I...
俺は…
I wanted to be like you...
お前の…ように…なりたかった…
But...
でも…
It's too late now.
もう…なれねぇ…
Bro...
あにき…あっ！
I see.
そうか…
Give it back.
返せ…
You're...
お前は…
Give it back.
返せ…
You're not human. That's why...
人じゃ…ないから…
It's just like with the ghost fox.
前の…化けギツネんときと一緒だ…
He beat a demon,
but isn't getting any body parts back.
鬼神を倒したのに、身体が戻らねぇ
Oh dear...
こいつは…
-Give it back!
-Stop it, bro!
返せぇ！
やめてくれよ！あにき！
It's my body!
俺の！身体だ！
No, this isn't right.
こんなの…こんなの酷すぎるよ！
Young Master.
若、あれを
What the...?
これは…
Please bro, stop...
もう…やめてくれよ…あにき
Bro?
あにき？
Where are you going?
どこ行くんだよ
Daigo.
醍醐…
That's where my body is.
そこに…俺の身体がある
Wait, bro!
まっ…待ってくれよ！あにき！
One cannot escape one's fate.
背負った因果からは…逃れられねぇか…
Such a heavy burden.
なんとも難儀なことだよ…
Is it his fate to bear it?
これもまた因果…か
Born into this world
There is no salvation
The distorted shape of the heart
Yet it beats courageously
There is no turning back
Even from the path of evil
Witnessing the withering seasons
We search for the truth
In our ugliness
We don't even recognize the pain
As we peel back the skin
We are forever tormented by our stupidity
But if the dawn never comes
Through the painful night
You who distrusts nothing
You will be able to love
this accursed world
Now that we carry the world
on our shoulders
It's time to take it back
"Nue"